HANNAH ROSE

GAME DEVELOPER

A highly adaptable senior programmer with 6 years professional experience in indie game studios working remotely, 10 years of professional programming experience, and a background in game jams and education.

My main priorities as a programmer are good communication with the team, and building extendible tools that let designers work fully independently of me, and features which solve as many problems as possible in one.

Experienced speaker and mentor. Comfortable communicating with other disciplines to accomodate their needs, and enjoy explaining and teaching others.

CONTACT

hannaesthetic.r@gmail.com







KEY SKILLS

Unity Development

C#

Shader Development

UI/UX

Localization

Tools Programming

Git

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Bithell GamesTRON Catalyst

Senior Programmer, April 2023 - Current

Isometric story driven action game. Built all level design tools, the framework level designers used to build level logic, level persistance, and pathfinding for objectives. Built the framework that let designers implement enemy AI and combat encounters. Integrated the dialogue framework, as well as building tools to export and import localization spreadsheets from all in game text, implemented all the UI.

TRON Identity

Programmer, Bithell Games, August 2021 - April 2023

Detective visual novel. As the main programmer on the project, was responsible for most of the game's implementation, including the narrative framework, UI, puzzle game, localization, and some of the VFX.

ARCSMITH

Freelance Programmer, Bithell Games, August 2020 - August 2021

VR puzzle/engineering game for the Meta Quest. Was the main programmer brought in after prototyping. Heavy focus on optimization work to get the game running on Quest 1 hardware. Also implemented cutscene, audio, game flow, save/load systems.

Spooky Doorway

The Darkside Detective: A Fumble In The Dark

Freelance Programmer, November 2019 - August 2020

Point and click detective game, the second title in the series. Addressed issues with the game engine that wouldn't scale to a bigger game, and implemented the new functionality needed. Set up source control and code review practices.

Weather Factory BOOK OF HOURS

UI Focused Programmer, June 2019 - September 2019

Prototyping work for sequel to BAFTA nominated Cultist Simulator. Focus on user input, technical art, and building an engine where designers and artists could build and write content without having to touch the game engine.

Immersive Studios

Junior Programmer, October 2018 - June 2019

Programmer at a VR/AR agency. Did VR and web development, as well as mobile apps for corporate clients.

Code Kingdoms

Course Designer, July 2015 - July 2018

Programming education company. Built and implemented a curriculum of over 40 projects where children would learn to make a game in Roblox or a Minecraft mod, as a means to learn programming.

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science, University of Warwick